ANDY FERNANDEZ - FULL STACK DEVELOPER

DENVER, CO | 720-220-2335 | andy.w.fernandez@gmail.com | Linkedin | GitHub

SUMMARY

Full-Stack software engineer proficient in using Javascript for front-end and back-end programming, React, HTML, CSS, API implementing, Node.JS, Express, PostgreSQL, and frameworks like Bootstrap. Experienced in the fields of Data and GIS analysis and automation.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, iQuery

Backend: Node.js, Express, RESTful APIs, and PostgreSQL

Tools: Mocha, Chai, Knex, Git, GitHub, Heroku, Node Package Manager, Visual Studio Code, Tableau, ArcGIS, QGIS,

and Jupyter Notebook

Additional Skills: Bilingual, Data Analysis, GIS Analysis, Python, R programming, and Spatial Statistics

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Movie Database Application | Link

10/2022

- Assembled the back end of a movie website, allowing users to search for their favorite movies.
- Used CRUD methods for reviews, and viewing theaters and movies that are showing.
- Applied router and controller functions to retrieve a user's specific requests.
- Technology: Node.js, Express, and Knex. Version control with Git.

Restaurant Reservation Application | Link

1/2023

- Full stack reservation and table management system.
- Implemented react-router and express to build a RESTful API in order to make HTTP requests for all of the reservation data stored on the connected PostgreSQL database.
- Created CRUD functions and knex queries to handle data going to and coming from the database.
- Used Git to track changes and versions while keeping sensitive information from being pushed to repositories.
- Technology: React, Node.js, Express, Knex, and PostgreSQL.

Study Tool Application | Link

09/2022

- Created an application that allows users to create, edit, and delete decks and cards within them.
- Created a REST API and middleware functions to allow user(s) to create, read, update and delete.
- Defined routes and URLs, and used state over multiple components.
- Technology: JavaScript, React, Express, Knex, HTML, and CSS. Progress/Versions tracked with Git.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

En Engineering

Denver, CO

GIS Technician

02/2019 - 02/2020

- Automated complicated GIS data analysis, resulting in an 83% decrease in processing time with Python.
- Collaborated on pipeline design, implementation, and automation in ArcMap and Small World.
- Managed massive amounts of incoming pipeline data, cleaning, organizing, and prioritizing aspects of the data based on client needs.

Century 21

Real Estate Agent

Denver, CO

12/2020 - 01/2022

Balanced the urgent needs of multiple clients and responded to deadlines in a timely fashion.

- Guided and trained home buyers through complicated processes.
- Obtained and negotiated resources to properly satisfy client needs.

EDUCATION

Thinkful

Online 08/2022 -12/2022

Certificate, Full Stack Software Engineering

- Learned industry best practices and software development standards with a focus on Javascript, HTML5, CSS3, React Native, Node.js, PostgreSQL, RESTful APIs, algorithms, and data structures.
- Developed and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks, spending several hours per week collaborating with and learning from senior web developers in a mentor-student relationship.

Google

Certificate, Google Data Analysis University of Colorado Boulder Bachelor of Arts, Geology

04/2022-06/2022 Boulder, CO 08/2012-12/2016